Mss.B.M58.1
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Asa Gray, Feb. 28, 1859; 7x7-3/4; Trego, Charles B., 1794-1874
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. with initials. 1p. and end. Copy. Asks how the Massachusetts society for the promotion of agriculture settled their Michaux legacy, for the APS might like to do likewise.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, March 4, 1859; 10x8; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Explains how the Massachusetts society for the promotion of agriculture acquired title to their Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s G[reely] Loring, Boston, April 6, 1859; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Trego, Charles B., 1794-1874
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. with initials. 1p. and end. Copy. Asks how the Michaux legacy could be transferred to the APS.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, April 18, 1859; 10x8; Massachusetts Society for Promoting Agriculture
    Boston, A.L.S.: Richard S. Fay. 2p. and end. Explains how the Michaux bequest was secured.
  - Letter to [George Bacon] Wood, May 1862; 4x6; Bossange, Hector
    Hotel de Londres, [ca.]. A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Encloses letter from Beziers, Mrs. Michaux' husband [in re Michaux legacy]. For enclosures, see Beziers to Bossange May 1, 1862. Presented by College of Physicians; Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to Dr. [G.B.] Wood, May 1862; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Bossange, Hector
    [Lundi]. A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. M. Germain is expecting them. In re: Michaux legacy. Presented by the College of Physicians, Jan. 1949.
  - Power of attorney for the securing of the Michaux legacy, Feb. 22, 1862; 10-1/2x8-1/4; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p.and end.
  - Summons to the American Philosophical Society to intervene to secure their claim to the Michaux legacy, Feb. 22, 1862; 10-1/2x8-1/4; France, Pontoise. Sheriff of
    D. 3p., end.
  - Letter to Sauvain, Philadelphia, Feb. 24, 1862; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Germain, A., (Alexandre), 1809-1887
    Pontoise, L.S. 2p. Copy. Concerning the Michaux legacy. On same sheet is copy of letter from same to same; March 7, 1862.
  - Letter to [Sauvain], March 7, 1862; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Germain, A., (Alexandre), 1809-1887
    Pontoise, L.S. 1p. and end. Copy. Concerning the Michaux legacy. On same sheet as letter from same to same; Feb. 24, 1862.
  - Letter to A. Germain, March 28, 1862; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy for the APS.
  - Letter to [George B.] Wood, March 28, 1862; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; King, Edward, d. 1873.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: Edward King, E. Durand 2p. Relative to the Michaux legacy. Presented by the College of Physicians, Jan. 1949.
  - Minute, April 4, 1862; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p. and end. Extract. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] B. Wood, April 7, 1862; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: J. P. Lesley, secy. 2p. and end. Relative to the Michaux legacy. Presented by the College of physicians; Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to Edward King and E[lie Magliore] Durand, April 15, 1862; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p., end. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Hector Bossange, May 1, 1862; 5-1/4x8; Beziers, Adolphe
    Vauréal, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy. Enclosed originally in letter from Bossange to G.B.Wood; ca. May 1862. Presented by College of Physicians; Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to Dr. [G.B.] Wood, May 9, 1862; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Bossange, Hector
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. In re: Michaux legacy. Presented by the College of Physicians, Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to [J. Peter] Lesley, May 12-15, 1862; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Paris, A.L.S. 6p., end. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [George B. Wood], May 13, 1862; 5 1/4" x 8"; Bossange, Hector
    Mardi A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Has not yet received a reply to their telegra, [in re: the Michaux legacy]. Presented by the College of Physicians, Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to [Hector] Bossange, May 13, [1862]; 7-1/2x10; Beslay, E.
    Pontoise, Telegram. 1p. In French. Relative to meeting with M.Germain in re: Michaux legacy. Presented by the College of Physicians; Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to [G.B.] (George Bacon) Wood, [May 1862]; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, June 16, 1862; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [G.B.] Wood, June 30, 1862; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Germain, A., (Alexandre), 1809-1887
    Pontoise, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. In re: Michaux legacy. Presented by the College of Physicians, Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to [A.] Germain, July 9, 1862; Bossange, Hector
    Paris, A.L. Transcribed in letter from Bossange to G.B.Wood, In French. In re: Michaux legacy. Presented by the College of Physicians, Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to Geo. B. Wood, July 9, 1862; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Bossange, Hector
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. In re: Michaux legacy; transcribes letter to M. Germain, Presented by the College of Physicians, Jan. 1949.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, July 10, 1862; 8x5-1/2; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    London, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, London, Dec. 21, 1863; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Bossange, Gustave
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning the Michaux legacy. Forwards books for the APS. Refers to Wood and Hector Bossange.
  - Letter to the minister of justice of France, May 1867; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    L. 1p. and end. Inqures of Germain and the APS Michaux legacy.
  - Report of committee on the Michaux legacy, May 1867; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Eli K. Price, E. Durand, F. Fraley and Cha[rle]s B. Trego. 3p. and end.
  - Letter to Madame [Bezier], May 14, 1867; 7-1/4x4; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy. Attached to same sheet is letter and translation from Bezier to Durand; July 14, 1868.
  - Letter to Madame Bezier, May 17, 1867; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Vauréal, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Asks for information pertaining to A. Germain and the APS Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, June 10, 1867; 10x7-3/4; Strong, William
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and end. E. O. K[endall], and end. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [George Bacon] Wood, March 23, 1868; 8x5-1/4; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and end. by F. F[raley]. Concerning the Michaux legacy. Hector Bossange could be agent for the APS.
  - Minute, June 19, 1868; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    A.D.S.: Tho[mas] P. James, Librarian. 1p. and end. Orders Hector Bossange agent for the APS to secure the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to E[lie Magloire] Durand, Philadelphia, July 14, 1868; 7-1/4x4 8x5; Beziers, Madame Michaux
    Vauréal, L. 2p. and add. In French. ----Translation of 1p. Concerning the Michaux legacy. Attached to same sheet as letter from Durand to Mme. Bezier; May 14, 1867.
  - Letter to Eli K[irk] Price, Nov. 12, 1868; 8x5; Robinson, Moncure, 1802-1891
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p., end. Recommends Carlier as APS member and as agent to secure Michaux legacy.
  - Power of attorney to Auguste Carlier to secure the Michaux legacy, 1868; 12-1/4x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
  - Letter to [Elie Magloire] Durand, Feb. 9, 1869; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Paris, L. 2p. Copy. Concerning the Michaux legacy. On same sheet as letter from E. Durand to E. K. Price; Feb. 26, 1869.
  - Letter to Eli K[irk] Price, Feb. 26, 1869; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. Translates letter concerning the Michaux legacy. On same sheet is letter from Carlier to Durand; Feb. 26, 1869.
  - Letter to E[lie Magloire] Durand, Philadelphia, April 16, 1869; 6-3/4x4-1/4; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. ----Translation. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to E[lie Magloire] Durand, April 23, 1869; 12x7-1/2; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Paris, L.S. 2p. Secures the Michaux legacy for the APS.
  - Letter to E[lie Magloire] Durand, June 14, 1869; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    L. 2p. Copy. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy. Refers to Wood. On same sheet as letter from Durand to E. K. Price; June 28, 1869.
  - Letter to Ely [sic] K[irk] Price, June 28, 1869; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and enc. of 2p. Concerning the Michaux legacy. On same sheet is copy of letter from Carlier to Durand; June 14, 1869.
  - Letter to E[lie Magloire] Durand, Philadelphia, Aug. 19, 1869; 7X4-1/4, 8-1/2x5-1/4; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Passy, A.L.S. 4p. In French. ----Copy. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Elias [sic Magloire] Durand, Philadelphia, Sept. 12, 1869; 8x5; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. and add. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] B[acon] Wood, Oct. 25, 1869; 8x5-1/4; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p., add. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to commissioners of Fairmount Park, Oct. 1869; 10x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    L.S.: Eli K. Price, E. Durand and Chas. B. Trego. 2p. and end. Wishes to use part of Michaux legacy for trees for the park.
  - Preamble and resolutions concerning the Michaux grove of oaks provided by the Michaux legacy of the APS, March 12, 1870; Fairmount Park Commission (Philadelphia, Pa.).
    D.S.: David F. Foley, Secy. 2p. and end. Enclosed originally in letter from Foley to E. K. Price; March 14, 1870.
  - Letter to Eli K[irk] Price, March 14, 1870; 7x8; Fairmount Park Commission (Philadelphia, Pa.).
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. From David H. Foley, concerning the Michaux grove in Fairmount park provided by the APS Michaux legacy. For enclosure, see: Phila. Fairmount park commissioners. Preamble...; March 12,1870.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Leslie [sic], June 17, 1870; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Price, Eli K., (Eli Kirk), 1797-1884
    A.L.S. 1p. Death of Mme. Michaux Bezier and news of the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [Elie Magloire Durand], June 28, 1870; 7x4-1/4; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Passy, A.L.S. 3p. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [Elie Magloire Durand], Aug. 8, 1870; 8-1/2x5; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Paris, L. 3p. Copy. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy. On same sheet as letter from Durand to Lesley; Aug. 24, 1870.
  - Letter to [Elie Magloire Durand], Aug. 8, 1870; 7x4-1/4; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. In French. Current events. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [J.] P[eter] Lesley, Philadelphia, Aug. 24, 1870; 8-1/2x5; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Annapolis, A.L.S. 3p. and enc. of 2p. In French. Sends copy of letter from Carlier concerning the Michaux legacy. On same sheet is copy of letter from Carlier to Durand; Aug. 8, 1870.
  - Letter to [Elie Magloire Durand?], Sept. 15, 1870; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    L. 2p. and end. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to the [American Philosophical Society], 1870; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    L.S. 1p. Incomplete. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [Elie Magloire Durand], May 8, 1871; 8x5-1/2; Carlier, Auguste, 1803-1890
    L. 1p. Mutilated. In French. Concerning the Michaux legacy.
  - Statement of accounts of the Michaux legacy paid to the commissioners of Fairmount Park, Jan. 1872 - Nov. 1888; 12-1/2x15-1/4; American Philosophical Society
  - Statement to Eli K[irk] Price of the use of the Michaux legacy in purchasing oaks for Fairmount Park, June 5, 1876; 10-1/2x8, 14x8-1/4; Fairmount Park Commission (Philadelphia, Pa.).
    Philadelphia, D.S.: R. W. Robbins, sec. 2p. and end.
  - Resolution concerning the expenditure of the Michaux legacy for trees for Fairmount Park, Nov. 17, 1876; 8-1/4x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
  - Resolution that the Michaux committee report on proposed expenditures, April 6, 1877; 2-1/2x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
  - Resolution to fill vacancies on the Michaux committee caused by the deaths of Durand, Trego and Guillon, April 6, 1877; 2-1/2x5-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p., end.: J. B. Townsend, A. H. Smith and W. M. Tilghman, and end.
  - Report of Michaux committee on course of forestry lectures by Rothrock, April 25, 1877; 9-3/4x7-3/4 and 2-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Eli K. Price. 2p. and end.
  - Letter to J. P. Lesley, May 4, 1877; 10x8; Fraley, F., (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Reports on Michaux legacy.
  - Report of Michaux committee that trees from Fairmount Park be planted on University of Pennsylvania grounds, Sept. 8, 1877; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
  - Report of Michaux committee on forestry lectures by Rothrock, March 15, 1878; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    A.D.S.: Eli K. Price. 1p. and end.
  - Report of Michaux committee on grant for forestry lectures by Rothrock, March 18, 1880; 9-3/4x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
  - Letter to F[rederick] Fraley, June 17, 1880; 8x5; Price, Eli K., (Eli Kirk), 1797-1884
    A.L.S. 1p., end. by M[ary] L[esley], and add. Request for photograph to be made from Michaux portrait. Suggests others be made for botanists and institutions. Refers to T. Meehan, Henry Shaw, and Shaw's garden.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, March 12, 1881; 11x8-1/2; Fairmount Park Commission (Philadelphia, Pa.).
    Philadelphia, Printed L. filled in in ms. S.: F. M. Doughery, secretary. 1p. and end. Thanks for painting of F. A. Michaux.
  - List of members on the committee for the Michaux legacy, March 6, 1885; 7-1/2x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 14, 1885; 9x5-3/4; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p., end. Will accept position for supervising the F. A. Michaux legacy to the A.P.S.
  - List of members on the reconstructed committee for the Michaux legacy, March 20, 1885; 8x3; American Philosophical Society
  - Report of committee on the use of the Michaux legacy, Jan. 19, 1887; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: J. Sergeant Price. 1p. and end. ----Copy. Recommends purchase of plates of Florida botany by Rothrock.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, Philadelphia, April 2, 1887; 9-3/4x8; Drexel, Harjes & Co.
    Paris, L. 3p. and end. Business of the Michaux legacy, signed Hayes.
  - Minute, May 6, 1887; 9x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D. 2p., end. Concerning Michaux legacy. F. Fraley and. J. S. Price are mentioned. Cf. Minutes, May 6, 1887.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Nov. 7, 1887; 10x8-1/2; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Informs the APS the Michaux lectures on forestry will be held at the University
  - Report of the committee on the use of the Michaux legacy, Nov. 11, 1887; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: J. Sergeant Price. 2p. and end. ----Copy. Forestry lectures to be given by Rothrock at the University
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Nov. 22, 1887; 10x8-1/2x9-1/2x7-1/2; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and enc. of 1p. and end. Encloses information to go on the tickets of admission for the Michaux forestry lectures he will deliver at the University.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 27, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Thayer, Russell
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Would like to use Michaux legacy money for trees for Fairmount park.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, Philadelphia, Aug. 7, 1888; 10x8; Drexel, Harjes & Co.
    Paris, L. 1p. and end. Concerning the income from the Michaux legacy.
  - Resolution authorizing the payment of the Michaux legacy's income to the treasurer of the society, Oct. 19, 1888; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
  - Letter to Thomas Meehan, Nov. 1, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Suggests using the income from the Michaux legacy for lectures on forestry. Enclosed originally in letter from Meehan to Price; Nov. 2, 1888.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Nov. 2, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Enc. Concerning expenditures from the Michaux legacy for Rothrock's lectures on forestry. For enclosure, see: Rothrock to Meehan; Nov.1, 1888.
  - Letter to H[enry] M. Fisher, Nov. 5, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Birkinbine, John
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerning publishing Rothrock's lectures on forestry (subsidized from the Michaux legacy). Refers to Henry Phillips, Jr. and the APS.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 5, 1888; 10x8; Fernow, B. E. (Bernhard Eduard), 1851-1923
    Washington, Typed L.S. 2p. and end. Suggest that the APS use part of the income from the Michaux legacy for a forestry exhibit at the Paris exposition. Refers to Rothrock.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 6, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Thinks the APS should use the Michaux legacy income for exhibit on forestry at the Paris exposition.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 7, [1888]; 7x4-1/2; Fisher, Henry M.
    A.L.S. 3p., end. Asks permission of the APS for Rothrock to use Michaux legacy material in a publication on forestry.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, Philadelphia, Nov. 9, 1888; 7-3/4x5; Drexel, Harjes & Co.
    Paris, Printed L. filled in in ms. 1p. and end. Will pay interest from the Michaux legacy to Price.
  - Letter to W[illiam] V. McKean, Nov. 10, 1888; 5-1/2x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    L. 1p. and end. Extract. Concerning the disposition of the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to J[ohn] S[ergeant] Price, Nov. 15, 1888; 11x8-1/2
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: H[enry] R[enno] Heyl. 2p. and end. Would be glad to provide room for the Rothrock lectures on forestry which the Michaux fund subsidizes.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Nov. 15, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning lecture room for his forestry lectures, sponsored by the Michaux legacy. Refers to Franklin Institute and the University.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Nov. 22, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning the Michaux lectures on forestry at Franklin institute. Refers to the Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Philadelphia, Nov. 27, 1888; 10x8; Fernow, B. E. (Bernhard Eduard), 1851-1923
    Washington, Typed L.S. 2p., end. APS must rush its plans if it uses the Michaux income for Paris exposition. Mass society has Michaux fund to use, too.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Nov. 28, 1888; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    [endorsed] A.L.S. 1p., end. Wishes the committee on the Michaux legacy to meet.
  - Report of committee on the Michaux legacy that Rothrock be given money for lectures on forestry, Nov. 30, 1888; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: J. Sergeant Price. 2p. ----Copy.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Dec. 8, 1888; 11x8-1/2
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: H. R. Heyl. 1p. and end. Has reserved hall for the Michaux lectures on forestry to be delivered by Rothrock.
  - Receipt to Franklin institute for advertising Rothrock's Michaux lectures on forestry, Jan. 5, 1889; 4x7-3/4; Philadelphia Evening Bulletin
    Philadelphia, Printed D. filled in in ms. S.: S. F. McCormick. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Jan. 18, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Desires the APS to use the Michaux legacy for the Paris exposition.
  - Bill for printing cards for Rothrock's Michaux lectures on forestry, Jan. 30, 1889; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Avril Printing Company
    Philadelphia Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p., add: J. Sergeant Price, end.
  - Letter to William V. McKean, March 21, 1889; 10-1/2x8, 12-1/2x8; Thayer, Russell
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 4p., with list of 2p. Reports on trees purchased by funds from the Michaux legacy for use in Fairmount part. Includes complete list of trees.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 10, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Smith, Aubrey H, ca. 1813-1891
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of Proceedings which contains Michaux's journal.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Philadelphia, Oct. 6, 1889; 10x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p., end. Presents to the APS subjects for the Michaux sponsored lectures on forestry.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Oct. 10, 1889; 10x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Hopes to get Academy of Natural Sciences room for Michaux lectures of forestry.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Oct. 15, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Gives APS subjects for Michaux lectures on forestry, to be given at the Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Report and resolution of the Michaux legacy committee on Rothrock's lectures on forestry, Nov. 4, 1889; 13x8 and 3x8; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: J. Sergeant Price. 2p. and end. ----Copy of report.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Nov. 7, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Gives dates for his Michaux forestry lectures to be held at the Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Report of the committee on the Michaux legacy and trees for Fairmount Park, Nov. 8, 1889; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: W[illiam Samuel], W[aitman] Ruschenberger, J. Cheston Morris, George H. Horn, and W[illiam] V. McKean. 3p. and end.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Jan. 7, 1890; 11x8-1/2; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. pertaining to the Michaux legacy. Concerning the Academy of Natural Sciences botanical expedition to Mexico and request for APS funds.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Jan. 14, 1890; 11x8-1/2; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Academy of Natural Sciences is sending a botanical expedition to Mexico. Recommends Michaux grant to aid it.
  - Report of committee on the Michaux legacy on grant to the botanical expedition to Mexico, Jan. 31, 1890; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: Thomas Meehan. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Sept. 29, 1890; 10-1/4x7-3/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p. Asks for grant from the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Sept. 30, 1890; 10-1/4x7-3/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Asks for grant from the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, Oct. 7, 1890; 9x5-1/2; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Approves Rothrock's request for grant from Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to Thomas Meehan, Oct. 20, 1890; 9x5-3/4; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. From Academy of Natural Sciences; concerning his report on trees of Mexico to the APS [from the expedition granted sum from the Michaux legacy].
  - Report of committee on the Michaux legacy on the Mexican botanical expedition and Rothrock's request, Oct. 28, 1890; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: J. Sergeant Price. 2p. and end.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Oct. 28, 1891; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Estimates his expenses for Michaux forestry lectures. Hopes to use Academy of Natural Sciences hall.